I have startling new information about this video that's been going around the internet.
This is Officer Dana Elmore, and she uses excessive force in the unlawful arrest of
24-year-old Micaiah Washington. I've been in contact with Micaiah's attorney,
attorney Leroy Maxwell from the Maxwell Tillman Law Firm, and I've received new information that
you need to know. But first, let me show you the video in case you haven't seen it.
Trigger warning, police brutality.
Before I go over what he was charged with after all that, let me give you the two minutes that led
up to that video. 24-year-old Micaiah Washington was changing his tire on the side of the road
when Officer Dana Elmore approached him in her car. She began asking Micaiah what he was doing,
and Micaiah informed her, I'm changing my tire. She asked to see a driver's license. He asked,
why do I got to give you my driver's license to change a tire? She asked for more information,
multiple times asked for his driver's license. He told her, I don't need to give you my driver's
license. I'm just changing my tire. And it was at that point that he pulled his cell phone out
to begin recording the interaction. But he never got a chance to, because before he could even
start recording, she tased him. Upon being tased, his phone fell to the ground, he fell to the ground
and put his hands behind his back, and she cuffed him. After cuffing him, she put one foot on his
back, standing on his back, and then made what appeared to be a call to another officer. At that
point, Micaiah's brother started filming, and that's where the video picks up that you watched.
Now, it's very important to note that Officer Dana Elmore did not know Micaiah's brother was
filming. As you saw in the video, she put him on the hood, went through his pockets, and found a
firearm. She didn't like that he was asking questions, and she began tasing him in the back,
as you saw in the video. It's also very important to note that the only thing she pulled out of his
pocket in that video was a firearm. So now, knowing that, look what they charged him with.
Right here, drug trafficking. Officer Dana Elmore claimed that after pulling the firearm out,
she pulled out seven grams of fentanyl. They also charged him with possession of a firearm by a felon.
They charged him with simple possession of marijuana, resisting arrest, and obstructing governmental
operations. But guess what happened next? The video that Micaiah's brother filmed went viral on
the internet. And it was only then that they found out there was a video of the arrest. And it was then
that the state's attorney filed a motion to null press the drug trafficking charge. Null press means
basically they're not going to press those charges. They're dropping the charges. Not the judge,
the state's attorney. And let's read the motion, may we? It said the suspected narcotics were seized in
connection with the arrest of the defendant. The video shows they were not. The suspected
narcotics were field tested prior to the arrest. Wait a minute. If they seized him during the arrest,
how'd they field test him prior to the arrest? Because that never happened. But then it says
in the motion, further testing has since been conducted that failed to yield a positive result
for fentanyl. You know what that means? I firmly believe that means they were planning on planting
evidence to frame him for drug trafficking. That's my opinion on why they now can't yield
a positive result. And because of that, he was under a $500,000 bond. But that has now been null
press. Oh, and the ex-felon in possession of a firearm? He's not a felon. That's not even real.
So that's also expected to be null press. If not null press, the judge will drop it anyway. The court's
going to dismiss it. He's not a felon. Because of the trafficking charge being gone and the other
stuff being null press, his consolidated bond now is only $5,000 instead of $500,000 that it was
before. So to recap, Officer Dana Elmore harassed and brutalized 24-year-old Micaiah Washington simply
for changing his tire while black. And I firmly believe they were going to plant evidence on him
and charge him with drug trafficking. All charges against Micaiah Washington should be dropped. All.
And Officer Dana Elmore, who's currently on administrative leave or paid vacation,
should be charged with assault and battery and for lying. So here's the call to action. Email and call
the district attorney. We want all charges against Micaiah Washington dropped. And we want charges
against Dana Elmore brought up immediately.